# DANIEL WIEST, PE

danieljwiest.dev • 509-860-5434 • dwiest4@gmail.com • Portland, Oregon

# RELEVANT SKILLS

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Experience With: Node, Express, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Git, AWS, Jest
- Database Management: MongoDB, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL
- Familiar With: C++ and Python
- Skilled In: Microsoft Office Suite, AutoCAD, PLS-CADD

#### **GENERAL**

- Diverse engineering, project management, and personnel management experience
- Strong interpersonal communication skills
- Extensive professional experience working with multi-disciplinary design teams and both internal and external partners
- Self-motivated learner with demonstrated history of adapting to new technologies

# **PROJECTS**

## CUBE COBRA | AWS, DynamoDB, JavaScript, React

Contributions to an open source web service for Magic: The Gathering Cube
management. Goals: Participate in an open source project and gain experience
working within a larger code base.

# PORTFOLIO WEBSITE | JavaScript, TypeScript, React, CSS

 Portfolio website for hosting resume, highlighting project work, and illustrating front-end design. URL: danieljwiest.dev

### **VERMELHO GAME** | JavaScript, TypeScript, React, CSS

 Web-based implementation of popular Azul board game. Goals: Gain experience managing complex state, complete larger project with React, and implement TypeScript on a project.

### **EXERCISE TRACKER** | Node, Express, MongoDB

• Exercise logging web service. Goals: Complete back-end design for a web service; setup and manage database for the web server

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### HDR ENGINEERING, INC.

Consulting Engineer | Portland, OR 12/2022 - Present Section Manager | Portland, OR 08/2020 - 12/2022

- Manage Oregon transmission engineering team
- Lead engineer on multi-million dollar design program
- Drive local business and client development
- Mentor and train junior engineers on transmission line design
- National leader in transmission lattice tower analysis

•	Project Engineer   Portland, OR	01/2015 - 08/2020
•	Design Engineer, EIT II   Portland, OR	07/2013 - 01/2015
•	Design Engineer, EIT I   Billings, MT	05/2011 - 07/2013

08/2006 - 05/2010

# EDUCATION & LICENSURE

#### GONZAGA UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING & APPLIED SCIENCES

• Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, Cum Laude

#### **PROFESSIONAL ENGINEER**

•	State of Washington, License Number 53377	12/2015 - Present
•	State of Oregon, License Number 96310PE	07/2020 - Present